### Monish Narwani

#### Software Developer L2

A self-motivated & dynamic Software Developer with a good background in computer science and has vast experience in Web apps development & DevOps. In a nutshell, I could be an asset to your organization, who can help in problem-solving & collaborating with teams to build products effectively. I have experience of more than four years working on JavaScript, AWS, Python, Laravel, Docker.



narwanimonish@gmail.com

8080690808

Ulhasnagar, India

linkedin.com/in/narwanimonish in

@narwanimonish

github.com/narwanimonish



#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Software Developer L2**

Focalworks Solutions Pvt Ltd

04/2019 - Present

Mumbai, India

### **Software Developer L1**Focalworks Solutions Pvt Ltd

06/2017 - 03/2019

Mumbai, India

Achievements/Tasks

- Contributed to teams from decision-making strategies to development & deployment.
- Independently contributed to POC's like migrating independent tasks on AWS lambda, & storing images on AWS S3 which decreased server load by 40%.
- Responsible for migrating ≈ 3000 users & their portfolios from Wordpress to Drupal.
- Helped teams with time-critical deadlines projects to be delivered on time.

#### Internship

#### Focalworks Solutions Pvt Ltd

01/2017 - 05/2017

Mumbai, India

Achievements/Tasks

- Developed a Time tracking app that automates Project Managers' task of generating time reports.
- Actively participated in the Shoutout project used internally to give shoutouts to employees.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor's - Computer Engineering**Vivekanand Education Society's Institute Of Technology

07/2014 - 06/2017

8.6/10 CGPI 3.6/4 IGPA

Courses

 Final project was "Social Media Analytics for Ecommerce Organizations"  Won 1st prize for LBS project "Vehicle Location Tracking System".

# **Diploma - Information Technology**S. H. Mansukhani Institute of Technology, Ulhasnagar

06/2011 - 06/2014

FIRST CLASS Distinction - 81.44%

#### **SKILLS**

Javascript AWS Python Docker GIT

SQL Django Node.js PHP-Laravel

#### **PROJECTS**

Trualta - Care Network (01/2020 - Present) 🗷

- This application is subscribed by ≈ 40 clients comprising of caring agencies and provinces of the US & Canada.
- Dockerized this Laravel application to use with Docker Swarm on HIPPA compliant platform.
- Integrated AWS SES mail events with application to have reports of user engagements.

Close2real - EKG Training (12/2018 - 12/2019) 🗗

 Created custom XBlock for Assessment player & deployed on Open EdX platform.

SplitSecondPix - Marathon Photography - India (08/2018 - 12/2018) ☑

- This application is used by ≈10,000 users & concurrently used ≈500 users when a new event is live.
- Deployed this application on AWS using services EC2, S3, AWS Lambda, & RDS.
- Decreased 40% of server load by migrating independent tasks to AWS Lambda

#### **CERTIFICATES**

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure 2021 Certified Architect Associate (12/2021 - Present) ☑

Modern React with Redux [2020 Update] - Stephen Grider (06/2020 - Present) ♂

AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate - Stephane Maarek (02/2020 - Present) ♂

AWS Solutions Architect - Associate Certification - Cloud Academy (08/2019 - Present) 

☑\*

Programming Data Structures & algorithms in Python - NPTEL (04/2019 - Present) ☑

#### **LANGUAGES**

Enalish

Hindi

Full Professional Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency